Okay, so we have our game mechanics down for our main character.
Now we need to do the same for our ball.
Firstly, we want to get our ball bouncing around the screen before we try to get it to interact with
the with the soccer player.
So how can we get our ball to randomly bounce around the screen?
Well, let's give it a shot.
Let's grab the when flag clicked and also bring in a forever loop.
Also, we know it has something to do with motion.
So let's have a look to see what we could use.
We know we can move the ball across the screen by changing its X position.
And there is a neat block that says if on edge bounce, which sounds hopeful.
So let's bring both of these into our script and clicking play.
Hmm.
No, that's not quite what we want.
The ball is just moving to the right side of the screen and bouncing when it hits the edge, which is
kind of to be expected.
So this change x by is clearly not the block that we need.
But before I continue, try to play around with the blocks and see if you can get it right.
Come on, just pause and give it a try.
So did you manage to figure it out?
Well, let's see how we can fix this.
Firstly, this change X is not what we want, so let's get rid of it.
Now remember how with our first program, I told you not to use the move ten steps block because we
can't make it go up and down.
Well, that's not quite true, because you actually can't.
You see, when we move ten steps, we are moving ten steps in whatever direction the sprite is facing.
So if our sprite were facing up, we would move up.
This is all to do with direction, and the direction of a sprite can be set over here or by these code
blocks.
Anyway, we won't worry too much about how direction works right now, as you'll get good at it in our
upcoming games.
But what you should know is when we bounce off the edge, it will point the sprite in a random direction
that is opposite to the wall it is bouncing off.
So with that all in mind, if we put the moving block in here instead, notice how our ball bounces
across the screen just how we want it.
So we are getting there with our game mechanics.
Next, we need to connect both of these sprites so we can start getting some headers going.